No one in history has fumbled YouTube as
much as me.
Some of you may notice I have a much
bigger channel that I don't really use
anymore.
I'm going to explain as to why I would
abandon a channel with 400,000
followers,
and at the same time tell you why it
is so important that those of you
with a personal brand start a YouTube
channel if you don't have one already.
Or for a lot of you that have one,
to start using it more.
So let's go to the analytics behind what I
call my main channel.
It's not really my main channel.
[chuckles] Now,
how many people do you know that
have been locked out of their YouTube
account for years?
Because I was for four years.
I forgot my logins.
So I used that as an excuse not to post.
Then I made a comeback, then died a bit,
then I made a comeback.
Now, here's the important thing,
estimated revenue, £113,000.
And straight away you're thinking,
"Oh my God, that's great." Well,
considering
I've had the channel for nine years,
it's not. It's minimum wage.
And over here you might go, "But James,
you're getting 7,000 views a day." Cool.
Yeah. In that respect, you're right.
And I have had some videos go mega viral.
However, I grew this channel,
I think looking back now,
just trying to be YouTube
famous.
I saw everyone else with the silver play
buttons and was like, "I want one
of those." And since then,
I've been operating a channel with one
thing in mind, to
make money. I don't mind saying
that either.
I don't think that's a bad thing to say,
because every social media creator isn't
making content for the love of it.
They're making content in a bid to get new
clients.
I was a personal trainer for years on the
gym floor, and the only reason I
started on social media
was so I didn't have to walk the floor.
Do you know how disheartening it is?
You get £40 a session,
then the next hour you're going up to
people, "Hey mate,
I've just seen something you're doing
there." "Piss off." "Yeah, cheers."
Cool. So the point
that really hit home for me was
when we launched
Noonic. We made a little release video,
put it out there, and I got
destroyed. People called me a sellout,
grifter, every horrible insult under the
sun. I was like, "Wow,
I've been putting out content for you guys
for years.
Some of these videos took me three weeks
to make, and the second I try and bring
out my own product, you guys
are going to hate on me."
And I realized that a lot of
that audience, not the whole audience,
but a lot of them, they kind of only
followed me because I
was taking down AG1 or whatever.
And when it came to me trying to promote a
business, they were like, "Shut up.
Go take down another company.
That's what I followed you for." So that's
when I
realized I had to start a new channel.
Now, this channel
that you're watching here, again,
had very few followers.
So I started this in January 2024.
So this channel's two years old.
And look, the
growth was so slow to begin with.
It took me six months to get
to
4,000 subscribers, posting quite a lot.
Then it took me a year to get to 20K,
and then a year later, we're at
50K. So if we say that doubles every year,
could be 100K, there'll be another one
of those back there, then 200, et cetera.
Now the beautiful thing here
is imagine saying to someone,
your YouTube will double
every year as long as you keep posting.
That's insane.
100K next year,
that means potentially double the revenue.
200K the next year,
potentially double the revenue.
You see why this excites me so much.
But we all start from zero.
We all eat shit.
Even though you could argue that I was,
quote unquote, "well-known
online,"
fucking six months there for 500 new
subscribers.
I have to eat shit as much as anyone else.
So the reason that I want to really draw
your attention to this is
a lot of people now online
are using AI to appear more intelligent.
There's something called chauffeur
knowledge, and what that means
is imagine I'm a
nuclear physicist
and I'm going around the UK doing tours on
nuclear physics.
And I've got a driver, and my driver says,
"James, mate, I've heard you do this
talk so much,
I could take the next one." So I go,
"Do you know what, mate?
Why don't you take the next one?" So we go
to the next venue.
My driver goes up onto the stage
and he starts giving a talk on nuclear
physics.
Someone in the stage stands up
and asks him a really difficult question
about
nuclear physics. You might think this
is the period that he just cripples and,
"Oh,
no.
I'm a fraud." My driver on stage will just
go, "That's such an easy
question.
Let me get my driver in the audience to
answer it." And he would point to
me. This is called chauffeur knowledge,
where people pretend to have the knowledge
that they have when they don't,
and should they get challenged on it,
they just
push it to someone else. This
is where I think live streams
are about to make a bit
of a comeback. So the other day,
I did a live stream.
Well, not the other day, three months ago.
And it's 2 hours and 20 minutes long.
Now, I was doing a one-to-one-
Some of the videos are 7- ...
with one of my clients earlier,
and this is the thing that I showed them.
Oh, look at that, one out of 10. Oh.
Oh. One out of 10. Now, for this live,
we had
8,000 views. And on YouTube, people think,
"Oh, only 8,000 views?
Only 49 subscribers?"
But here's the point I want to show you.
Right?
In the last 48 hours,
53 people have watched this.
It's over three months old.
It's a live stream from over three months
ago. 50 people have watched it.
Traffic sources are a bit sporadic,
of course.
We have here the messages from the actual
live.
Here are the concurrent viewers, which
is pretty good.
Got up to 850, average about 600.
Now this is the bit I want to show you.
This retention graph looks like the video
bombed and died, but if you look at it
carefully, average view duration,
20 minutes, or 19 and a half
minutes. Now,
if you look back to a video
that we did three months ago.
Three months ago, one view an hour,
average view duration 20 minutes.
So every hour,
someone's watching for 20 minutes.
So that means for every two people
that drop off, one person watches an hour.
Now this is just ticking away,
and the reason that I love YouTube
is YouTube is my
best employee out of anyone in my team.
YouTube works seven days a week,
24 hours a day, and it goes out of its way
to do the hard parts of marketing for me.
Now,
the reason I'm making this video as well
is I've invested a lot of money into
YouTube courses, nearly $20,000.
And the first course I joined, five grand,
was crap.
Second one I joined was amazing. 10 grand.
Learnt so much.
And I've devised my own. Now,
there's going to be a link down in the
description
where you can buy it. It's $199. Now,
I was going to sell this maybe
2,000.
Then I was going to sell it for maybe
1,000.
But if I'm really real with you,
I always have this crippling insecurity
that what
I've made isn't good enough.
It's why I undercharge for my business
mentorship.
I'm always like, "Oh, is it worth that?
Oh, is it worth that?" So the way
that I've positioned it
is I'm going to heinously
undercharge for it because it teaches you
everything you need to, to grow your
YouTube channel and not to make the
mistakes I did.
And then over time,
I'm going to get you guys to help give me
feedback because it's
a $1,000 course. But if I sell it for 199,
you guys can say, "Hey, James, I need
you to expand here.
Maybe add another thing for this about
thumbnails. Could we get this?
Then over time,
I can build it up similar to what I did
with the mentorship.
So really for the first 300 people
that buy it,
it's going to be an introductory
rate. So check that out. Now,
the other thing I want to show you here
is this video
is 400, one year and 52 days old.
It took three months for
it to go viral,
then it started going viral.
In the last 48 hours, 600 views.
It's over a year old, and it's
still consistently getting me 300 views a
day.
I'm not paying, I'm not boosting,
I'm not running any ads.
YouTube is working all the time around the
clock to do this.
Then I can even tell you in real time what
those 600 views are equating
to.
I think because we've changed the title
here, give or take $14,000.
So let's have a look at this full
blueprint video,
and you notice I have this one
as my channel trailer.
So the last video has made me $7 to
$14,000.
This one here, again, 600 views,
300 views a day.
It's over a year old as well,
so that's 1,200 views a day from two of my
old
videos. Now this one,
3,000 subscribers called this one,
has gradually just
continued to crash,
and this one has done me $23,000.
So $17,000 from Business Mentorship,
four from Content Mastery,
14 from the PT Starter Kit,
and even here with the bundle,
even though the
conversions aren't massive between 5%,
0.85%, people are
going to be joining my lead magnet slowly.
If you look at 25,000 clicks,
a lot of people...
Sorry, if you look at 2,800 clicks,
that's people joining lead magnets.
Not to mention this could be the video
they watch, and they go to another video,
or
they go to the website,
or they buy direct, whatever it is.
These videos here,
you think before the big channel,
the famous channel, the
one with the silver play button,
making me minimum wage.
These ones are making me six months'
salary in a single video.
The video only took me two hours to make.
This is why I'm so excited for people to
start a
YouTube channel. And the reason
that I made this course is this.
I haven't even got monetization turned on
for this channel because I don't care.
On this channel,
it's just not important because this
is only about good
quality leads and people that
are right for doing business with me.
Some people watch these videos,
and they think, "Oh, James is a dickhead.
He's only talking about money." Some
people haven't even realized that this
is a
different channel altogether.
And the beautiful thing here is,
by YouTube
standards,
if you look at my latest videos, 8,000,
7,000, 9,000,
9,000, 5,000, 7,000, 13,000.
If I said to you, "I want you to make
a YouTube channel,
and I only want you to aim to get 3,000
views a video," you'd
go, "Yeah, I could probably do
that in 6 to 12 months." If you do that,
you're
going to get so many high-quality leads.
Now again, this channel,
nearly $5 million in rev.
Is it all profit? No.
I've run it about profit margin,
about 55%.
So I lose 40% in ads, then costs,
then my manager, whatever.
But you guys won't have the structures
there in place like I do.
183 videos, 50,000 subscribers, two years,
two
million a year. Now
is the time to start on YouTube.
Making videos, doing live streams.
This one here is with a cheap camera.
That's just a cheap camera plugged in with
a USB-C cable.
That's in my spare room at home. Right,
that one's died.
[laughs] That one's not getting views
anymore because the thumbnail's shit.
If you're not using YouTube now,
because I've done it the wrong way,
I'm now doing
it the right way,
you're really missing out.
If you said to me, "James,
you have to lose the 50,000 on your
Instagram or the
50,000 on YouTube," I'd say take the
Instagram all day, every day.
If anything,
I'd just clip up bits to go over on there.
There are millions of people on YouTube,
and I just think there's never been an
opportunity to pump out long-form content.
And the best part is short form,
you really need to plan the hooks,
the reels, the
setups, everything you have. I'm in.
Want to know the truth?
I'm in a pair of Speedos. I
was just sat in the sauna.
I was having a sauna downstairs,
and I thought, "Do you know what?
I'm going upstairs to make a video." Came
here, hit record, got it going, put it
together because I was like,
silver play button course is out today.
It's heinously cheap.
You guys can get access to it,
and you probably think, what's
your angle?
I'll tell you what my angle is.
The silver play button course will be two
grand in time.
I just need your feedback to confidently
enough raise the prices.
I'd much rather let you guys in for cheap
than raise prices later.
And the second thing
is probably about 10% of you will upsell
to my mentorship.
You get in, you go fucking, "Oh, this
is good." So there's going to be a link
there
in the description. Please purchase it.
And how about this?
If you don't absolutely love it,
email me james@newtonic.com.
I'll kick you out and refund you.
If you are not getting leads from YouTube
right
now, you're missing out.